And now back to
The World of Gross Sea Life.
现在回到
海洋生物的世界。
Observe how this ingenious
parasitic isopod
观察这个巧妙的
寄生等足类动物
finds a new home by attaching
itself inside a fish's mouth,
通过附着找到新家
本身在鱼嘴里，
becoming its new tongue.
成为它的新语言。
Hmm?
唔？
That's the most disgusting thing
I've ever seen.
这才是最恶心的事
我曾经见过。
Disgustingly genius!
令人厌恶的天才！
It's giving me a wonderful idea!
它给了我一个绝妙的主意！
I'll glue myself
to SpongeBob's tongue!
我会把自己粘起来
海绵宝宝的舌头！
By hiding right in
that fry cook's face,
通过隐藏在
炸厨师的脸，
I'll be in the perfect position
我会处于完美的位置
to collect
a Krabby Patty sample!
收集
蟹肉饼样品！
Well, what could possibly
go wrong?
嗯，什么可能
出问题了吗？
Clever disguise? Check.
巧妙的伪装？查看。
Sample container? Check.
样品容器？查看。
Glue? Check.
胶水？查看。
Time to begin
operation tongue oppressor!
开始时间
压舌器手术！
An iron a day
keeps the wrinkles away!
一天一熨斗
让皱纹远离！
Ooh. I hope it's a salesman!
哦。希望是个推销员！
Candy-gram!
糖果克！
Ooh! I just love
a Poetry-Slam Candy-gram!
哦！我就是爱
诗歌大满贯糖果克！
Poetry? Well, okay.
诗？好吧，好吧。
Roses are red, candy is sweet.
玫瑰是红的，糖果是甜的。
Uh, eat with your mouth,
not with your feet?
嗯，用嘴吃饭
不是用脚吗？
Words to live by.
赖以生存的话。
That's it! Eat the
delicious little plankton.
就是这样！吃
美味的小浮游生物。
I'll just have one little candy.
我只要一颗小糖果。
Who am I kidding?
我在跟谁开玩笑呢？
Come on, you dolt! Eat me.
来吧，你这个笨蛋！吃我吧
Ooh. This pink candy
looks so delicious...
哦。这颗粉色的糖果
看起来很好吃...
Yes. Yes.
是的。是的。
That I saved it just
for you, Gary!
我刚刚保存了它
为了你，加里！
Ugh.
啊。
I have to get inside
that mouth breather's mouth.
我必须进去
那个呼吸者的嘴。
Maybe disguise myself
as a door to door dentist?
也许伪装自己
作为上门牙医？
No, that's not a thing.
不，那不是一件事。
Ew! I stepped in some old gum!
呃！我踩到了一些旧口香糖！
And now, I just have
to glue myself
而现在，我只有
把我自己粘起来
to his hideous tongue.
到他那可怕的舌头。
Come on. Whoops!
快点。哎呀！
Yes!
是的！
Mm-hmm.
嗯嗯。
"The Tiny Book
of Tortuous Tongue Twisters."
《小书
曲折的绕口令。”
Perfect for my morning
exercises.
非常适合我的早晨
练习。
My tongue has to be in tip top
shape to taste my patties.
我的舌头必须处于顶端
形状来品尝我的肉饼。
Tongue twisters?
绕口令？
"The squad of odd cod
“奇怪的鳕鱼小队
applaud the sassy cephalopod."
为时髦的头足类动物鼓掌。”
The pain! Huh?
痛苦！啊？
This dream scheme
gone full steam
这个梦想计划
全速前进
guarantees Eugene's screams.
保证了尤金的尖叫声。
Oh, boy. Now, I'm doing it.
哦，男孩。现在，我正在做。
Morning, Squidward.
早上好，章鱼哥。
Ugh. Your breath
smells like chum.
啊。你的呼吸
闻起来像密友。
It is a bit stinky.
有点臭。
You try passing through
a snail's intestines
你尝试穿越
蜗牛的肠子
and see what you smell like!
看看你闻起来是什么味道！
A little breath spray
should help.
一点呼吸喷雾
应该有帮助。
Better get some patties out of
the freezer for today's orders.
最好拿出一些肉饼
存放今天订单的冰箱。
Oh, no! We're out of patties!
哦，不！我们的肉饼没了！
Of course, you are.
当然，你是。
Which means I get to make
a whole new batch!
这意味着我可以做
全新一批！
Hooray!
万岁！
Even better!
甚至更好！
I'll have a front-row seat
to the whole process.
我会坐在前排
到整个过程。
A little secret ingredient A.
一点秘密成分A。
Secret ingredient A?
秘密成分A？
Two plops of B.
两声扑通 B.
Some C, D, E, and G!
一些 C、D、E 和 G！
Two cups of this! A jar of that!
两杯这个！一罐那个！
And just a pinch of Z.
还有一点Z。
What's this guy making?
Alphabet soup?
这家伙在做什么？
字母汤？
Mix well.
搅拌均匀。
Perfect!
完美的！
Now for the taste test.
现在进行口味测试。
That's it, baby.
就是这样，宝贝。
I only need one sample.
我只需要一份样品。
My eye!
我的眼睛！
Ugh. These patties
are kind of bland.
啊。这些肉饼
有点平淡。
I can't taste them at all.
我根本尝不出它们的味道。
Time to get a little creative.
是时候发挥一点创意了。
Hmm, maybe some
Limburger cheese will help.
嗯，也许有一些
林堡奶酪会有帮助。
Oh, no. Not Limburger.
哦，不。不是林堡。
Still blah.
还是废话。
Ooh! How about
a little sauerkraut?
哦！怎么样
一点酸菜？
Flying Dutchman peppers.
飞翔的荷兰人辣椒。
And this old jar of toe jam.
还有这罐旧脚趾酱。
Good, Neptune.
Not in your mouth!
很好，海王星。
不在你嘴里！
Still doesn't have any taste.
还是没有什么味道。
Oh. I've made a critical error.
哦。我犯了一个严重错误。
My glue has covered
that dolt's taste buds.
我的胶水已经覆盖了
那个笨蛋的味蕾。
Get a move on, SpongeBob!
继续前进吧，海绵宝宝！
The orders are piling up!
订单堆积如山！
No problem, Squidward.
没问题，章鱼哥。
I guess
it'll have to do.
我猜
必须这样做。
The Krabby Patties are ready,
Squidward.
蟹黄饼就做好了
章鱼哥。
Whatever.
任何。
Thank Neptune. I'm starving.
感谢海王星。我饿死了。
Finally.
最后。
Is this even food?
这还是食物吗？
Ew! This is disgusting!
呃！这太恶心了！
I'll never eat here again!
我再也不会在这里吃饭了！
I've had better garbage!
我吃过更好的垃圾！
It tastes worse than chum!
味道比密友还差！
Hmm.
唔。
Worse than chum?
比密友还糟糕？
What have you done
to my patties?
你做了什么
到我的肉饼？
I'm sorry, Mr. Krabs.
对不起，蟹老板。
The patties
have no flavor at all today.
肉饼
今天一点味道都没有。
No flavor?
没有味道？
More like too much flavor!
更像是味道太多了！
They taste like the
Flying Dutchman's long johns!
它们的味道就像
飞翔的荷兰人的秋裤！
I'm afraid your taste buds
are worn out, boy-o.
我担心你的味蕾
都累坏了，小伙子。
Phew.
唷。
Until your tongue recovers,
直到你的舌头恢复正常
you're off grill duty.
你已经下班了。
Turn in your hat and spatula.
交出你的帽子和抹刀。
Aww.
哇。
That's one more
for the failure pile.
这还有一个
为失效桩。
Time to abandon tongue.
是时候放弃舌头了。
Ah, blast.
啊，爆炸。
The zipper's covered in glue.
拉链上沾满了胶水。
Huh. My left armpit
still sounds a little sharp.
呵呵。我的左腋下
听起来还是有点尖锐。
That's better.
这样更好。
Hey, SpongeBob.
嘿，海绵宝宝。
Hey, Patrick.
嘿，帕特里克。
What's the matter?
怎么了？
I can't taste a thing.
我尝不出任何东西的味道。
My tongue is broken.
我的舌头断了。
He goes to Patrick for advice?
他去找帕特里克寻求建议？
It's the nitwits
leading the dimwits.
这是一群白痴
带领愚人。
Your tongue's
probably just dirty.
你的舌头
可能只是脏了。
That happens to me all the time.
这种事经常发生在我身上。
You're the smartest
smart person who ever smarted!
你是最聪明的
曾经聪明过的聪明人！
Give me a little run off music,
maestro!
给我一点音乐，
大师！
- Ahh.
- Sweet Neptune!
- 啊。
- 甜蜜的海王星！
No!
不！
I need
something stronger.
我需要
更强大的东西。
This should do the trick!
这应该可以解决问题！
Ahh!
啊！
May I borrow
your hat, sir?
我可以借用吗
先生，你的帽子吗？
Oh, of course!
哦，当然！
It tastes like emptiness.
尝起来就像是空虚。
Tastes fine to me.
对我来说味道不错。
Oh, my poor tongue
is just worn out.
哦，我可怜的舌头
只是破旧了。
Guess it's time for a new one!
猜猜是时候换新的了！
What?
什么？
Ahh.
啊。
Silly me.
愚蠢的我。
Why didn't I do this earlier?
我为什么不早点这样做呢？
Can I borrow that
dirty old tongue of yours?
我可以借那个吗
你那脏兮兮的老舌头？
Of course!
当然！
Patrick eats more
Krabby Patties than anyone.
帕特里克吃得更多
蟹肉饼比任何人都多。
Why didn't I do this earlier?
我为什么不早点这样做呢？
Sorry, my old tongue's
a little loud.
抱歉，我的老舌头
有点大声。
That's okay.
没关系。
Perfect.
完美的。
I'm just gonna go grab
a bite to eat
我只是要去抢
吃一口
at the annual
Chum Eating Contest!
在每年的
密友吃比赛！
Chum eating contest?
密友吃比赛？
Was that today?
那是今天吗？
On your marks,
在你的标记上，
get set,
准备好，
chum!
密友！
Aw. Why can't I have
a detachable tongue?
噢。为什么我不能拥有
可拆卸的舌头？